[
  {
    "Question": "In equilibrium, the change of free energy is",
    "OptionA": "Maximum",
    "OptionB": "Minimum",
    "OptionC": "Zero",
    "OptionD": "N.O.T",
    "CorrectOption": "Zero"
  },
  {
    "Question": "In p-shaped orbitals, there is a difference in",
    "OptionA": "Size",
    "OptionB": "Shape",
    "OptionC": "Orientation",
    "OptionD": "N.O.T",
    "CorrectOption": "Orientation"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Reaction which gives a negative sign",
    "OptionA": "Exothermic",
    "OptionB": "Endothermic",
    "OptionC": "Thermochemical",
    "OptionD": "N.O.T",
    "CorrectOption": "Endothermic"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Sudden expansion of Gas is called?",
    "OptionA": "Joule Thomson Effect",
    "OptionB": "Dalton's Effect",
    "OptionC": "Avogadro's effect",
    "OptionD": "N.O.T",
    "CorrectOption": "Joule Thomson Effect"
  },
  {
    "Question": "The repetition of property at regular intervals is",
    "OptionA": "Regularity",
    "OptionB": "Uniformity",
    "OptionC": "Periodicity",
    "OptionD": "N.O.T",
    "CorrectOption": "Periodicity"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Formula which shows the exact number of atoms",
    "OptionA": "Molecular",
    "OptionB": "Empirical",
    "OptionC": "Both",
    "OptionD": "N.O.T",
    "CorrectOption": "Empirical"
  },
  {
    "Question": "One of the products during electrolysis of NaCl solution",
    "OptionA": "NaClo",
    "OptionB": "NaoH",
    "OptionC": "CloH",
    "OptionD": "N.O.T",
    "CorrectOption": "NaoH"
  },
  {
    "Question": "1 tore = ......... mm Hg",
    "OptionA": "1",
    "OptionB": "760",
    "OptionC": "670",
    "OptionD": "1000",
    "CorrectOption": "760"
  },
  {
    "Question": "S.I unit of pressure",
    "OptionA": "Pascal",
    "OptionB": "Atm",
    "OptionC": "Torr",
    "OptionD": "N.O.T",
    "CorrectOption": "Pascal"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Molecular Mass Of Water",
    "OptionA": "18 g",
    "OptionB": "18 a.m.u",
    "OptionC": "16 a.m.u",
    "OptionD": "16 g",
    "CorrectOption": "18 g"
  },
  {
    "Question": "The process of bond breaking and formation to produce a new substance is known as",
    "OptionA": "Chemical bond",
    "OptionB": "Physical Bond",
    "OptionC": "Both",
    "OptionD": "N.O.T",
    "CorrectOption": "Chemical bond"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Dehydration of Ethanol produces",
    "OptionA": "Ethene",
    "OptionB": "Ketone",
    "OptionC": "Aldehyde",
    "OptionD": "Carboxylic Acid",
    "CorrectOption": "Ethene"
  },
  {
    "Question": "A carbon atom carrying a positive charge and attached to three more atoms or groups is known as",
    "OptionA": "Hydronium Ion",
    "OptionB": "Oxanium ion",
    "OptionC": "Carbonium Ion",
    "OptionD": "Sulphonium Ion",
    "CorrectOption": "Carbonium Ion"
  },
  {
    "Question": "In ethane, all the bond angles are of",
    "OptionA": "217",
    "OptionB": "180",
    "OptionC": "120",
    "OptionD": "204",
    "CorrectOption": "120"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Benzene is a member of",
    "OptionA": "Alkanes series",
    "OptionB": "Saturated hydrocarbon",
    "OptionC": "Aromatic Hydrocarbon",
    "OptionD": "Alkyne series",
    "CorrectOption": "Aromatic Hydrocarbon"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Silver bromide is used in photography because",
    "OptionA": "Heat-sensitive",
    "OptionB": "Light-sensitive",
    "OptionC": "Both",
    "OptionD": "N.O.T",
    "CorrectOption": "Light-sensitive"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Bessemer's converters are used to get",
    "OptionA": "Aluminum",
    "OptionB": "Copper",
    "OptionC": "Chromium",
    "OptionD": "All",
    "CorrectOption": "Copper"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Boiling point of HNO3",
    "OptionA": "38 C",
    "OptionB": "96 C",
    "OptionC": "83 C",
    "OptionD": "98 K",
    "CorrectOption": "83 C"
  },
  {
    "Question": "When hydrogen occupies small spaces of matter, it is known as",
    "OptionA": "Ionic hydride",
    "OptionB": "Covalent Hydride",
    "OptionC": "Complex Hydride",
    "OptionD": "Interstitial hydride",
    "CorrectOption": "Interstitial hydride"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Chemical Formula Of Washing Soda Is ?",
    "OptionA": "Na2Co3.10H20",
    "OptionB": "NaoH",
    "OptionC": "CloH",
    "OptionD": "NOT",
    "CorrectOption": "Na2Co3.10H20"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Alkanes Are hydrogenated to",
    "OptionA": "Alkanes",
    "OptionB": "Alkenes",
    "OptionC": "Alkyls",
    "OptionD": "Alkaline",
    "CorrectOption": "Alkanes"
  },
  {
    "Question": "In ordinary hydrogen gas, the percentage of protium is?",
    "OptionA": "0.156",
    "OptionB": "99.98",
    "OptionC": "20.03",
    "OptionD": "NOT",
    "CorrectOption": "99.98"
  },
  {
    "Question": "A German Chemist Dobereneir In 1829 arranged similar elements into groups of three called",
    "OptionA": "Theresa",
    "OptionB": "Thrice",
    "OptionC": "Triades",
    "OptionD": "Tetrads",
    "CorrectOption": "Triades"
  },
  {
    "Question": "What is the measure of electromotive force?",
    "OptionA": "Joule",
    "OptionB": "Volt",
    "OptionC": "Column",
    "OptionD": "None",
    "CorrectOption": "Volt"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Atomic mass of tritium is",
    "OptionA": "0",
    "OptionB": "1",
    "OptionC": "2",
    "OptionD": "3",
    "CorrectOption": "3"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Water is ...",
    "OptionA": "Mixture",
    "OptionB": "Element",
    "OptionC": "Compound",
    "OptionD": "N.O.T",
    "CorrectOption": "Compound"
  },
  {
    "Question": "% Of Methane In Natural Gas;",
    "OptionA": "85%-90%",
    "OptionB": "90%-100%",
    "OptionC": "94%-95%",
    "OptionD": "91%-92%",
    "CorrectOption": "90%-100%"
  },

    {
      "Question": "Sodium is prepared by which method",
      "OptionA": "Electrolysis",
      "OptionB": "Hall-Heroult process",
      "OptionC": "Down's Process",
      "OptionD": "Bosch Process",
      "CorrectOption": "Down's Process"
    },
    {
      "Question": "Polar bond has which energy??",
      "OptionA": "Potential Energy",
      "OptionB": "Kinetic Energy",
      "OptionC": "Bond Energy",
      "OptionD": "Activation Energy",
      "CorrectOption": "Bond Energy"
    },
    {
      "Question": "If KC= [X^2]/[A][B]^t then the order of the reaction is",
      "OptionA": "Zero Order",
      "OptionB": "First Order",
      "OptionC": "Second Order",
      "OptionD": "Third Order",
      "CorrectOption": "Second Order"
    },
    {
      "Question": "In the period ionization energy",
      "OptionA": "Increase",
      "OptionB": "Decrease",
      "OptionC": "Same",
      "OptionD": "None",
      "CorrectOption": "Increase"
    },
    {
      "Question": "In the 10th Shell, bond length will be",
      "OptionA": "Shorter",
      "OptionB": "Longer",
      "OptionC": "Same",
      "OptionD": "None",
      "CorrectOption": "Longer"
    },
    {
      "Question": "Alkane preparation by reacting alkyl halide with (Na) metal is called??",
      "OptionA": "Wurtz Reaction",
      "OptionB": "Friedel-Crafts Reaction",
      "OptionC": "Cannizzaro Reaction",
      "OptionD": "Kolbe's Reaction",
      "CorrectOption": "Wurtz Reaction"
    },
    {
      "Question": "H1 isotope of hydrogen is called??",
      "OptionA": "Protium",
      "OptionB": "Deuterium",
      "OptionC": "Tritium",
      "OptionD": "Helium",
      "CorrectOption": "Protium"
    },
    {
      "Question": "Formula of nonyne is??",
      "OptionA": "C9H18",
      "OptionB": "C8H16",
      "OptionC": "C10H20",
      "OptionD": "C9H20",
      "CorrectOption": "C9H18"
    },
    {
      "Question": "If molecular mass is 180 and empirical formula is CH2O, Then what will be the molecular formula??",
      "OptionA": "C2H4O2",
      "OptionB": "C3H6O3",
      "OptionC": "C4H8O4",
      "OptionD": "C5H10O5",
      "CorrectOption": "C6H12O6"
    },
    {
      "Question": "Complete concentration of the substance is shown by",
      "OptionA": "Molarity",
      "OptionB": "Molality",
      "OptionC": "Normality",
      "OptionD": "None",
      "CorrectOption": "Molarity"
    },
    {
      "Question": "If temperature increases at constant pressure than volume will??",
      "OptionA": "Increase",
      "OptionB": "Decrease",
      "OptionC": "Remain the same",
      "OptionD": "None",
      "CorrectOption": "Increase"
    },
    {
      "Question": "Complex hydrocarbon used for body growth is called??",
      "OptionA": "Protein",
      "OptionB": "Vitamin",
      "OptionC": "Carbohydrate",
      "OptionD": "Lipid",
      "CorrectOption": "Protein"
    },
    {
      "Question": "Sugars which cannot break into other sugars are called",
      "OptionA": "Monosaccharides",
      "OptionB": "Disaccharides",
      "OptionC": "Polysaccharides",
      "OptionD": "Oligosaccharides",
      "CorrectOption": "Disaccharides"
    },
    {
      "Question": "Sodium metal reacting with alkyl halide forms???",
      "OptionA": "Alkane",
      "OptionB": "Alkene",
      "OptionC": "Alkyne",
      "OptionD": "All of the above",
      "CorrectOption": "Alkane"
    },
    {
      "Question": "Sulphuric acid is",
      "OptionA": "Di-protonic",
      "OptionB": "Mono-protonic",
      "OptionC": "Bi-protonic",
      "OptionD": "None",
      "CorrectOption": "Di-protonic"
    },
    {
      "Question": "Which one of the following is not a gas??",
      "OptionA": "Methane",
      "OptionB": "Propane",
      "OptionC": "Ethane",
      "OptionD": "Benzene",
      "CorrectOption": "Benzene"
    },
       
     { 
        "Question": "Nitric acid has boiling point......",
        "OptionA": "83°C",
        "OptionB": "100°C",
        "OptionC": "120°C",
        "OptionD": "150°C",
        "CorrectOption": "83°C"
      },

      {
        "Question": "Equilibrium established reaction of two phases is called..........",
        "OptionA": "Static",
        "OptionB": "Dynamic",
        "OptionC": "Heterogeneous",
        "OptionD": "Homogeneous",
        "CorrectOption": "Dynamic"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Kinetic molecular theory of gases main point MCQ???",
        "OptionA": "Particles in constant motion",
        "OptionB": "Negligible volume of gas particles",
        "OptionC": "Collisions are perfectly elastic",
        "OptionD": "All of the above",
        "CorrectOption": "All of the above"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Hess's Law of Heat states that???",
        "OptionA": "Energy is neither created nor destroyed",
        "OptionB": "The enthalpy change of a reaction depends on the stoichiometry of the reaction",
        "OptionC": "The enthalpy change is the same whether the reaction occurs in one or several steps",
        "OptionD": "Energy always flows from a region of higher temperature to a region of lower temperature",
        "CorrectOption": "The enthalpy change is the same whether the reaction occurs in one or several steps"
      },
      {
        "Question": "If KSP > ionic product then the solution will",
        "OptionA": "Saturated",
        "OptionB": "Unsaturated",
        "OptionC": "Supersaturated",
        "OptionD": "None",
        "CorrectOption": "Unsaturated"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Which one of the following is n-propyl??",
        "OptionA": "n-C3H7",
        "OptionB": "n-C4H9",
        "OptionC": "n-C5H11",
        "OptionD": "n-C6H13",
        "CorrectOption": "n-C3H7"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Hydrocarbon containing one group have a general formula",
        "OptionA": "CnH2n+2",
        "OptionB": "CnH2n-2",
        "OptionC": "CnH2n",
        "OptionD": "Not",
        "CorrectOption": "CnH2n+2"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Hydrocarbon contains C, O, H such that oxygen and hydrogen have the same ratio as that of water are called???",
        "OptionA": "Alcohol",
        "OptionB": "Aldehyde",
        "OptionC": "Ketone",
        "OptionD": "Ether",
        "CorrectOption": "Alcohol"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Carbon attached to three other carbons is called??",
        "OptionA": "Methyl",
        "OptionB": "Ethyl",
        "OptionC": "Propyl",
        "OptionD": "Butyl",
        "CorrectOption": "Propyl"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Wilson cloud chamber uses........................ alcohol",
        "OptionA": "Saturated",
        "OptionB": "Unsaturated",
        "OptionC": "Supersaturated",
        "OptionD": "None",
        "CorrectOption": "Saturated"
      },


      {
        "Question": "The repetition of a property at regular intervals is called its?",
        "OptionA": "Regularity",
        "OptionB": "Uniformity",
        "OptionC": "Punctuality",
        "OptionD": "Periodicity",
        "CorrectOption": "Periodicity"
      },
      {
        "Question": "The formula which shows the exact number of atoms?",
        "OptionA": "Empirical formula",
        "OptionB": "Molecular formula",
        "OptionC": "Structural formula",
        "OptionD": "None of the above",
        "CorrectOption": "Molecular formula"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Mass of an electron",
        "OptionA": "9.11x10^-21 kg",
        "OptionB": "9.11x10^-31 kg",
        "OptionC": "9.11x10^21 kg",
        "OptionD": "9.11x10^31 kg",
        "CorrectOption": "9.11x10^-31 kg"
      },
      {
        "Question": "At equilibrium, the change in free energy of the reaction is?",
        "OptionA": "Zero",
        "OptionB": "Maximum",
        "OptionC": "Minimum",
        "OptionD": "Any",
        "CorrectOption": "Zero"
      },
      {
        "Question": "When a compressed gas is allowed to expand suddenly, it produces cooling, this phenomenon is called?",
        "OptionA": "Joule-Thomson effect",
        "OptionB": "Joule-Kelvin effect",
        "OptionC": "Both a and b",
        "OptionD": "None of the above",
        "CorrectOption": "Both a and b"
      },
      {
        "Question": "A system that relates heat to the surroundings and enthalpy of the reaction is negative -ΔH by convention, this reaction is called?",
        "OptionA": "Endothermic",
        "OptionB": "Exothermic",
        "OptionC": "Both a and b",
        "OptionD": "None of the above",
        "CorrectOption": "Exothermic"
      },
      {
        "Question": "The internal energy of a fixed mass of an ideal gas depends on",
        "OptionA": "Pressure",
        "OptionB": "Temperature",
        "OptionC": "Volume",
        "OptionD": "All of the above",
        "CorrectOption": "All of the above"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Which is the lightest gas in the universe?",
        "OptionA": "Nitrogen",
        "OptionB": "Carbon dioxide",
        "OptionC": "Neon",
        "OptionD": "Hydrogen",
        "CorrectOption": "Hydrogen"
      },

      {
        "Question": "The chemistry of carbon is called:",
        "OptionA": "Organic chemistry",
        "OptionB": "Inorganic chemistry",
        "OptionC": "Physical chemistry",
        "OptionD": "Pharmaceutical chemistry",
        "CorrectOption": "Organic chemistry"
      },
      {
        "Question": "How many moles of sulphur are there in 64 grams of the element?",
        "OptionA": "1 mole",
        "OptionB": "2 moles",
        "OptionC": "3 moles",
        "OptionD": "4 moles",
        "CorrectOption": "2 moles"
      },
      {
        "Question": "A biological process brought about by the enzymes in the yeast or other micro-organism is called:",
        "OptionA": "Respiration",
        "OptionB": "Fermentation",
        "OptionC": "Photosynthesis",
        "OptionD": "Evolution",
        "CorrectOption": "Fermentation"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Lysine and bistodine are amino acids:",
        "OptionA": "Acidic",
        "OptionB": "Non-polar",
        "OptionC": "Basic",
        "OptionD": "Polar with neutral R-group",
        "CorrectOption": "Basic"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Some of them are also called undercoats:",
        "OptionA": "Fillers",
        "OptionB": "Drier",
        "OptionC": "Thinner",
        "OptionD": "Primers",
        "CorrectOption": "Primers"
      },
      {
        "Question": "A spontaneous change is one in which a system suffers:",
        "OptionA": "Increase in internal energy",
        "OptionB": "Lowering in free energy",
        "OptionC": "Lowering of entropy",
        "OptionD": "No energy change",
        "CorrectOption": "Lowering in free energy"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Which of the following systems is in equilibrium:",
        "OptionA": "An open pan of water is boiling on stove while temperature of water is constant.",
        "OptionB": "Water is freezing in an open ice box. Temperature of water is constant.",
        "OptionC": "An ant hill follows its daily cycle. The population of ant hill is constant.",
        "OptionD": "Balloon contains air and few drops of water; the pressure in the balloon is constant.",
        "CorrectOption": "Balloon contains air and few drops of water; the pressure in the balloon is constant."
      },
      {
        "Question": "When potassium permanganate is dissolved in water, the solution is:",
        "OptionA": "Oxidized",
        "OptionB": "Reduced",
        "OptionC": "Unreacted",
        "OptionD": "None of the above",
        "CorrectOption": "Oxidized"
      },
      {
        "Question": "When catalyst and reactants are present in the same phase, the catalyst is called:",
        "OptionA": "Homogeneous catalyst",
        "OptionB": "Heterogeneous catalyst",
        "OptionC": "Organic catalyst",
        "OptionD": "None of the above",
        "CorrectOption": "Homogeneous catalyst"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Pressure remaining constant, the volume of a given mass of gas is directly proportional to temperature:",
        "OptionA": "Charles law",
        "OptionB": "Boyle's law",
        "OptionC": "Gay Lussac's law",
        "OptionD": "Avogadro's law",
        "CorrectOption": "Charles law"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Diesel is the fraction of petroleum obtained in the temperature range of 220-350 °C and contains alkanes of:",
        "OptionA": "C6-C10",
        "OptionB": "C10-C13",
        "OptionC": "C13-C16",
        "OptionD": "C13-C25",
        "CorrectOption": "C13-C16"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Unequal sharing of an electron pair results in:",
        "OptionA": "Ionic bond",
        "OptionB": "Polar covalent bond",
        "OptionC": "Hydrogen bond",
        "OptionD": "All of the above",
        "CorrectOption": "All of the above"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Any property which depends upon the state of the system is called:",
        "OptionA": "Enthalpy",
        "OptionB": "State function",
        "OptionC": "Free energy",
        "OptionD": "Internal energy",
        "CorrectOption": "State function"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Le-chatelier's principle is a generalization which enables us to produce the effect of a change of:",
        "OptionA": "Pressure only",
        "OptionB": "Pressure, temperature & concentration",
        "OptionC": "Temperature & concentration",
        "OptionD": "Only temperature",
        "CorrectOption": "Pressure, temperature & concentration"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Reaction rate is expressed in units of:",
        "OptionA": "mole dm^-3 s^-1",
        "OptionB": "mole dm^-3",
        "OptionC": "mole dm^-3 N^-1",
        "OptionD": "dm^3 s^-1",
        "CorrectOption": "mole dm^-3 s^-1"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Coinage metals are elements of sub-group I-B and these include:",
        "OptionA": "Cu, Ag, Au",
        "OptionB": "Zn, Cd, Hg",
        "OptionC": "Fe, Co, Ni",
        "OptionD": "Cu, Zn, Ni",
        "CorrectOption": "Cu, Ag, Au"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Hydrogen, at ordinary temperature and pressure, exists in nature in the:",
        "OptionA": "Solid state",
        "OptionB": "Liquid state",
        "OptionC": "Gaseous state",
        "OptionD": "Plasma state",
        "CorrectOption": "Gaseous state"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Electrical conductivity of alkaline earth metals from Be to Ra:",
        "OptionA": "Remains disturbed",
        "OptionB": "Remains the same",
        "OptionC": "Increases",
        "OptionD": "Decreases",
        "CorrectOption": "Increases"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Aluminum reacts slowly with dil. H2SO4 to produce:",
        "OptionA": "Nitrogen gas",
        "OptionB": "Oxygen gas",
        "OptionC": "Hydrogen gas",
        "OptionD": "Sulfur dioxide",
        "CorrectOption": "Hydrogen gas"
      },
      {
        "Question": "The elements in which 'd' or 'f' orbitals are incomplete either in the atomic state or in their common ions are called:",
        "OptionA": "Transuranium elements",
        "OptionB": "Transition elements",
        "OptionC": "Lanthanides",
        "OptionD": "Actinides",
        "CorrectOption": "Transition elements"
      },
      {
        "Question": "2,4,6-trinitrotoluene is abbreviated as:",
        "OptionA": "TNA",
        "OptionB": "TAN",
        "OptionC": "TNT",
        "OptionD": "NTT",
        "CorrectOption": "TNT"
      },
      {
        "Question": "An alkyl halide reacts with an aqueous KOH solution to give an:",
        "OptionA": "Aldehyde",
        "OptionB": "Alkane",
        "OptionC": "Alcohol",
        "OptionD": "Acid",
        "CorrectOption": "Alcohol"
      },
      {
        "Question": "The maximum concentration of substrate above which an increase of substrate concentration does not increase the rate of reaction is called of enzyme with substrate:",
        "OptionA": "Termination",
        "OptionB": "Saturation",
        "OptionC": "Fluctuation",
        "OptionD": "Maximum optimation",
        "CorrectOption": "Saturation"
      },
      {
        "Question": "The elements required in the soil in small amounts are called:",
        "OptionA": "Micronutrients",
        "OptionB": "Macronutrients",
        "OptionC": "Mega nutrients",
        "OptionD": "Microscopic",
        "CorrectOption": "Micronutrients"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Magnetic specifies:",
        "OptionA": "Size of orbital",
        "OptionB": "Shape of orbital",
        "OptionC": "Orientation of orbital",
        "OptionD": "Nuclear stability",
        "CorrectOption": "Shape of orbital"
      },


      {
        "Question": "Natural gas contains ethene …………",
        "OptionA": "1 - 1.5%",
        "OptionB": "9-21%",
        "OptionC": "5-10%",
        "OptionD": "4.5-8%",
        "CorrectOption": "5-10%"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Phosphene is formed when hydrogen directly reacts with …………………..",
        "OptionA": "P",
        "OptionB": "N",
        "OptionC": "O",
        "OptionD": "S",
        "CorrectOption": "P"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Hydrogenation reaction occurs in vegetable oil, and the catalyst used is --------------------",
        "OptionA": "Ni",
        "OptionB": "Mn",
        "OptionC": "Ti",
        "OptionD": "Co",
        "CorrectOption": "Ni"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Positive charge ions are called ………………………………………..",
        "OptionA": "Anion",
        "OptionB": "Cation",
        "OptionC": "Both A and B",
        "OptionD": "Not",
        "CorrectOption": "Cation"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Alum is used to -------------- of water",
        "OptionA": "Purification",
        "OptionB": "Distillation",
        "OptionC": "Crystallization",
        "OptionD": "Not",
        "CorrectOption": "Crystallization"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Bleaching powder is prepared by the reaction of Cl2 with ----------",
        "OptionA": "Ca(OH)2",
        "OptionB": "CaCO3",
        "OptionC": "NaOH",
        "OptionD": "Not",
        "CorrectOption": "Ca(OH)2"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Alkali metals are ---------- conductors of electricity",
        "OptionA": "Good",
        "OptionB": "Bad",
        "OptionC": "Slow",
        "OptionD": "Fast",
        "CorrectOption": "Good"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Ionic and atomic radii in a period from left to right -----------------",
        "OptionA": "Increase",
        "OptionB": "Decrease",
        "OptionC": "Remain the same",
        "OptionD": "Calculate",
        "CorrectOption": "Decrease"
      },
      {
        "Question": "In transition elements, ionization potential left to right --------",
        "OptionA": "Increase",
        "OptionB": "Decrease",
        "OptionC": "Remains the same",
        "OptionD": "Calculate",
        "CorrectOption": "Increase"
      },
      {
        "Question": "In the periodic table, ionization from left to right ------------",
        "OptionA": "Increase",
        "OptionB": "Decrease",
        "OptionC": "Remain the same",
        "OptionD": "Calculate",
        "CorrectOption": "Increase"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Lyman series is found in -----------------------------------",
        "OptionA": "Ultra violet region",
        "OptionB": "Visible region",
        "OptionC": "Invisible region",
        "OptionD": "Not",
        "CorrectOption": "Ultra violet region"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Hydrogen spectrum gives series -----------",
        "OptionA": "1",
        "OptionB": "2",
        "OptionC": "3",
        "OptionD": "5",
        "CorrectOption": "3"
      },

      
  {
    "Question": "Hydrogen bomb is based on the principle of",
    "OptionA": "Nuclear fission",
    "OptionB": "Nuclear fusion",
    "OptionC": "Natural radioactivity",
    "OptionD": "Artificial radioactivity",
    "CorrectOption": "Nuclear fusion"
  },
  {
    "Question": "The Alkali metals are called good reducing agents. This implies that?",
    "OptionA": "They easily capture electrons",
    "OptionB": "They are not stable at room temperature",
    "OptionC": "They easily lose electrons",
    "OptionD": "They don't act with dilute acids",
    "CorrectOption": "They easily lose electrons"
  },
  {
    "Question": "In ethane all the bond angles are of",
    "OptionA": "217",
    "OptionB": "109.5",
    "OptionC": "120",
    "OptionD": "204",
    "CorrectOption": "120"
  },
  {
    "Question": "The process of bond breaking and bond formation to produce a new substance is known as?",
    "OptionA": "Chemical reaction",
    "OptionB": "Physical reaction",
    "OptionC": "Biological reaction",
    "OptionD": "None of the above",
    "CorrectOption": "Chemical reaction"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Unequal sharing of electron pair results in:",
    "OptionA": "Ionic bond",
    "OptionB": "Polar covalent bond",
    "OptionC": "Hydrogen bond",
    "OptionD": "All of the above",
    "CorrectOption": "All of the above"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Benzene is a member of?",
    "OptionA": "Alkane series",
    "OptionB": "Saturated hydrocarbons",
    "OptionC": "Aromatic hydrocarbon",
    "OptionD": "Alkyne series",
    "CorrectOption": "Aromatic hydrocarbon"
  },
  {
    "Question": "The one mole of H20 contains",
    "OptionA": "6.02x10^23",
    "OptionB": "2 x 6.02 x 10^23",
    "OptionC": "3 x 6.02 x 10^23",
    "OptionD": "3.01 x 10^23",
    "CorrectOption": "6.02x10^23"
  },
  {
    "Question": "A system that relates heat to the surroundings and enthalpy of the reaction is negative - H by convention, this reaction is called?",
    "OptionA": "Endothermic",
    "OptionB": "Exothermic",
    "OptionC": "Both a and b",
    "OptionD": "None of the above",
    "CorrectOption": "Exothermic"
  },
  {
    "Question": "In ethane all the bond angles are of?",
    "OptionA": "217",
    "OptionB": "109.5",
    "OptionC": "120",
    "OptionD": "204",
    "CorrectOption": "120"
  },
  {
    "Question": "The internal energy of a fixed mass of an ideal gas depends on?",
    "OptionA": "Pressure",
    "OptionB": "Temperature",
    "OptionC": "Volume",
    "OptionD": "All of the above",
    "CorrectOption": "All of the above"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Protons were discovered by?",
    "OptionA": "Faraday",
    "OptionB": "J.J. Thomson",
    "OptionC": "Goldstein",
    "OptionD": "",
    "CorrectOption": "Goldstein"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Which of the following elements have the lowest and highest boiling point in the Periodic table?",
    "OptionA": "Helium and Tungsten",
    "OptionB": "Hydrogen and Rhenium",
    "OptionC": "Helium and Rhenium",
    "OptionD": "Hydrogen and Tungsten",
    "CorrectOption": "Hydrogen and Rhenium"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Fats and oils are examples of?",
    "OptionA": "Proteins",
    "OptionB": "Vitamin",
    "OptionC": "Lipids",
    "OptionD": "Carbohydrates",
    "CorrectOption": "Lipids"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Significant figures of 807.30 are?",
    "OptionA": "5",
    "OptionB": "2",
    "OptionC": "3",
    "OptionD": "4",
    "CorrectOption": "5"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Which of the following has the shortest bond length?",
    "OptionA": "C-C",
    "OptionB": "C=C",
    "OptionC": "C≡C",
    "OptionD": "All",
    "CorrectOption": "C=C"
  },
  {
    "Question": "A carbon atom carrying a positive charge and attached to three more atoms or groups is called?",
    "OptionA": "Hydronium ion",
    "OptionB": "Oxanium ion",
    "OptionC": "Carbonium ion",
    "OptionD": "Sulphonium ion",
    "CorrectOption": "Carbonium ion"
  },
  {
    "Question": "What is the molecular mass of water (H2O)?",
    "OptionA": "18.015 g/mole",
    "OptionB": "36 g/mole",
    "OptionC": "8 g/mole",
    "OptionD": "16 g/mole",
    "CorrectOption": "18.015 g/mole"
  },
  {
    "Question": "In Cl2O2, the Oxidation no: of Cl is?",
    "OptionA": "+14",
    "OptionB": "+7",
    "OptionC": "-7",
    "OptionD": "-14",
    "CorrectOption": "+7"
  },
  {
    "Question": "In HF molecule, overlapping occurs?",
    "OptionA": "S-S",
    "OptionB": "S-P",
    "OptionC": "P-P",
    "OptionD": "None",
    "CorrectOption": "S-P"
  },
  {
    "Question": "The principle Quantum number describes the?",
    "OptionA": "Spin of electron",
    "OptionB": "Shape of orbital",
    "OptionC": "Distance from nucleus",
    "OptionD": "Number of orbitals",
    "CorrectOption": "Distance from nucleus"
  },

  {
    "Question": "Charles's law mathematically written as?",
    "OptionA": "K=V/T",
    "OptionB": "K=VT",
    "OptionC": "K=T/V",
    "CorrectOption": "K=T/V"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Volume is directly proportional to temperature at constant pressure. The law is called",
    "OptionA": "Boyle's law",
    "OptionB": "Charles's law",
    "OptionC": "Avogadro law",
    "OptionD": "None of these",
    "CorrectOption": "Charles's law"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Intermolecular attraction of an Ideal gas can be increased by?",
    "OptionA": "Pressure",
    "OptionB": "Temperature",
    "OptionC": "Heat",
    "OptionD": "None",
    "CorrectOption": "Pressure"
  },
  {
    "Question": "A balanced chemical equation is affected by_________?",
    "OptionA": "Temperature",
    "OptionB": "Pressure",
    "OptionC": "Catalyst",
    "OptionD": "All of them",
    "CorrectOption": "All of them"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Number of Moles of solute dissolved in 1kg of solvent is called_________?",
    "OptionA": "Molarity",
    "OptionB": "Hydration",
    "OptionC": "Molality",
    "OptionD": "Molar concentration",
    "CorrectOption": "Molality"
  },
  {
    "Question": "In equilibrium constant, the product is written as_____?",
    "OptionA": "Denominator",
    "OptionB": "Numerator",
    "OptionC": "Multiply",
    "OptionD": "None",
    "CorrectOption": "Numerator"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Borax chemical formula is given by__________?",
    "OptionA": "H3BO3",
    "OptionB": "Na2B4O7 10H2O",
    "OptionC": "NaCl",
    "OptionD": "All of these",
    "CorrectOption": "Na2B4O7 10H2O"
  },
  {
    "Question": "The compounds of carbon and hydrogen are studied in",
    "OptionA": "Bio-chemistry",
    "OptionB": "Organic chemistry",
    "OptionC": "Physical chemistry",
    "OptionD": "All of these",
    "CorrectOption": "Organic chemistry"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Sodium is used as _______?",
    "OptionA": "Reducing Agent",
    "OptionB": "Oxidizing Agent",
    "OptionC": "Gas",
    "OptionD": "None",
    "CorrectOption": "Reducing Agent"
  },
  {
    "Question": "The chemical formula of dichloromethane is_____?",
    "OptionA": "CH2CL2",
    "OptionB": "CH3Cl2",
    "OptionC": "CaO",
    "OptionD": "None",
    "CorrectOption": "CH2CL2"
  },
  {
    "Question": "When Hydrogen of alkane is replaced with halogen atoms resulting family is called?",
    "OptionA": "Alkyl Halide",
    "OptionB": "Alkyl group",
    "OptionC": "Alkyl",
    "OptionD": "Alcohol",
    "CorrectOption": "Alkyl Halide"
  },
  {
    "Question": "General formula of Alkane is?",
    "OptionA": "CnH2n_2",
    "OptionB": "CnH2n",
    "OptionC": "CnH2n+2",
    "OptionD": "None",
    "CorrectOption": "CnH2n+2"
  },
  {
    "Question": "In exothermic reaction heat is denoted by",
    "OptionA": "*H",
    "OptionB": "*Q",
    "OptionC": "Both *a and *b",
    "OptionD": "None",
    "CorrectOption": "Both *a and *b"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Saturated hydrocarbons are the compounds in which the valency of carbon is satisfied by_______?",
    "OptionA": "Single",
    "OptionB": "Double",
    "OptionC": "Triple",
    "OptionD": "None",
    "CorrectOption": "Single"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Normal propyl alcohol structural formula is?",
    "OptionA": "CH3-CH2-CH2-OH",
    "OptionB": "CH3-CH2-CHOH",
    "OptionC": "CH3-CH2-CH2-CH2-OH",
    "OptionD": "None",
    "CorrectOption": "CH3-CH2-CH2-OH"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Which orbital has lower energy?",
    "OptionA": "Atomic orbital",
    "OptionB": "Molecular orbital",
    "OptionC": "Ionic orbital",
    "OptionD": "None",
    "CorrectOption": "Atomic orbital"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Chemistry of Carbon is called.......................",
    "OptionA": "Organic Chemistry",
    "OptionB": "Inorganic Chemistry",
    "OptionC": "Physical Chemistry",
    "OptionD": "Analytical Chemistry",
    "CorrectOption": "Organic Chemistry"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "How many moles of the sulfur are there in 64 grams of element",
    "OptionA": "1 mole",
    "OptionB": "2 moles",
    "OptionC": "3 moles",
    "OptionD": "4 moles",
    "CorrectOption": "2 moles"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "A spontaneous change is the one in which system suffers...",
    "OptionA": "increase in internal energy",
    "OptionB": "lowering in free energy",
    "OptionC": "lowering of entropy",
    "OptionD": "No energy change",
    "CorrectOption": "lowering in free energy"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "Some of the .................... are also called undercoats",
    "OptionA": "Fillers",
    "OptionB": "Drier",
    "OptionC": "Thinner",
    "OptionD": "Primers",
    "CorrectOption": "Primers"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "Lysine and bistodine are................. amino acids",
    "OptionA": "Acidic",
    "OptionB": "Non polar",
    "OptionC": "Basic",
    "OptionD": "Polar with neutral R-group",
    "CorrectOption": "Basic"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "When potassium permanganate is dissolved in water, solution is",
    "OptionA": "Oxidized",
    "OptionB": "Reduced",
    "OptionC": "Uncreated",
    "OptionD": "None",
    "CorrectOption": "Oxidized"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "When catalyst and reactants are present in the same phase, catalyst is called",
    "OptionA": "Homogeneous Catalyst",
    "OptionB": "Heterogeneous Catalyst",
    "OptionC": "Organic Catalyst",
    "OptionD": "None",
    "CorrectOption": "Homogeneous Catalyst"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "Chemical Reaction Ratio is explained in the units of?",
    "OptionA": "Grams",
    "OptionB": "Moles",
    "OptionC": "Liters",
    "OptionD": "None",
    "CorrectOption": "Moles"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "Hydrogen at ordinary temperature and pressure exist in which state",
    "OptionA": "Gas",
    "OptionB": "Solid",
    "OptionC": "Liquid",
    "OptionD": "Plasma",
    "CorrectOption": "Gas"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "Electrical conductivity of Alkaline earth metals....................... from Be to Ra",
    "OptionA": "Increase",
    "OptionB": "Decrease",
    "OptionC": "Same",
    "OptionD": "Disturbed",
    "CorrectOption": "Increase"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "Le Chatelier's principle is a generalization which enables us to produce the effect of change of",
    "OptionA": "Pressure only",
    "OptionB": "Pressure, temperature, and concentration",
    "OptionC": "Temperature and concentration",
    "OptionD": "Only concentration",
    "CorrectOption": "Pressure, temperature, and concentration"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "Any property which depends on the state of the system is called..........................",
    "OptionA": "State Function",
    "OptionB": "State Variable",
    "OptionC": "State Property",
    "OptionD": "State Constant",
    "CorrectOption": "State Function"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "Unequal sharing of electron pair results in ............................ bond",
    "OptionA": "Ionic",
    "OptionB": "Covalent",
    "OptionC": "Coordinate Covalent",
    "OptionD": "Metallic",
    "CorrectOption": "Covalent"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "The elements required to the soil in small amount are called",
    "OptionA": "Microelements",
    "OptionB": "Macronutrients",
    "OptionC": "Trace Elements",
    "OptionD": "Micronutrients",
    "CorrectOption": "Micronutrients"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "The quantum numbers of 2p electron are??",
    "OptionA": "n = 2, l = 1, m = 0, s = -1/2",
    "OptionB": "n = 2, l = 0, m = 1, s = +1/2",
    "OptionC": "n = 2, l = 1, m = 1, s = -1/2",
    "OptionD": "n = 2, l = 2, m = 0, s = +1/2",
    "CorrectOption": "n = 2, l = 1, m = 1, s = -1/2"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "The combining capacity of an element with another element is called??",
    "OptionA": "Valency",
    "OptionB": "Atomic Number",
    "OptionC": "Mass Number",
    "OptionD": "Atomic Mass",
    "CorrectOption": "Valency"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "Which compounds have fast reaction?",
    "OptionA": "Ionic",
    "OptionB": "Covalent",
    "OptionC": "Coordinate Covalent",
    "OptionD": "Metallic",
    "CorrectOption": "Ionic"
  },
  {
    "Question": "The process of conversion of a solid directly into a gas is called?",
    "OptionA": "Sublimation",
    "OptionB": "Evaporation",
    "OptionC": "Condensation",
    "OptionD": "Fusion",
    "CorrectOption": "Sublimation"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "What is the SI unit of pressure?",
    "OptionA": "Pascal",
    "OptionB": "Newton",
    "OptionC": "Joule",
    "OptionD": "Watt",
    "CorrectOption": "Pascal"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "Which of the following is an example of a redox reaction?",
    "OptionA": "Combustion of methane",
    "OptionB": "Photosynthesis",
    "OptionC": "Neutralization of an acid with a base",
    "OptionD": "Polymerization of ethene",
    "CorrectOption": "Combustion of methane"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "What is the chemical formula for sulfuric acid?",
    "OptionA": "HCl",
    "OptionB": "H2SO3",
    "OptionC": "H2SO4",
    "OptionD": "HNO3",
    "CorrectOption": "H2SO4"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "Which gas is responsible for the greenhouse effect?",
    "OptionA": "Carbon dioxide",
    "OptionB": "Oxygen",
    "OptionC": "Nitrogen",
    "OptionD": "Methane",
    "CorrectOption": "Carbon dioxide"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "What is the molecular formula of glucose?",
    "OptionA": "C6H12O6",
    "OptionB": "C2H6O",
    "OptionC": "CH4",
    "OptionD": "CO2",
    "CorrectOption": "C6H12O6"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "Which element is a noble gas and commonly used in lighting?",
    "OptionA": "Helium",
    "OptionB": "Argon",
    "OptionC": "Krypton",
    "OptionD": "Neon",
    "CorrectOption": "Neon"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "What is the chemical symbol for gold?",
    "OptionA": "Ag",
    "OptionB": "Au",
    "OptionC": "Fe",
    "OptionD": "Cu",
    "CorrectOption": "Au"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "The study of the distribution and movement of groundwater in the soil is known as?",
    "OptionA": "Pedology",
    "OptionB": "Hydrology",
    "OptionC": "Edaphology",
    "OptionD": "Agronomy",
    "CorrectOption": "Hydrology"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "Which gas is evolved when a metal reacts with acid?",
    "OptionA": "Oxygen",
    "OptionB": "Hydrogen",
    "OptionC": "Carbon dioxide",
    "OptionD": "Nitrogen",
    "CorrectOption": "Hydrogen"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "The process of conversion of light energy into chemical energy in plants is called?",
    "OptionA": "Respiration",
    "OptionB": "Photosynthesis",
    "OptionC": "Fermentation",
    "OptionD": "Transpiration",
    "CorrectOption": "Photosynthesis"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "What is the common name for sodium bicarbonate?",
    "OptionA": "Baking Soda",
    "OptionB": "Washing Soda",
    "OptionC": "Borax",
    "OptionD": "Table Salt",
    "CorrectOption": "Baking Soda"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "Which gas is responsible for the pungent smell of rotten eggs?",
    "OptionA": "Oxygen",
    "OptionB": "Sulfur dioxide",
    "OptionC": "Hydrogen sulfide",
    "OptionD": "Methane",
    "CorrectOption": "Hydrogen sulfide"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "What is the chemical formula for methane?",
    "OptionA": "CH4",
    "OptionB": "C2H6",
    "OptionC": "CO2",
    "OptionD": "H2O",
    "CorrectOption": "CH4"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "Which metal is the best conductor of electricity?",
    "OptionA": "Copper",
    "OptionB": "Aluminum",
    "OptionC": "Silver",
    "OptionD": "Gold",
    "CorrectOption": "Silver"
  },
  {
    "Question": "What is the chemical formula for water?",
    "OptionA": "H2O",
    "OptionB": "CO2",
    "OptionC": "NH3",
    "OptionD": "CH4",
    "CorrectOption": "H2O"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "What is the chemical formula for table salt?",
    "OptionA": "NaCl",
    "OptionB": "KCl",
    "OptionC": "CaCl2",
    "OptionD": "MgCl2",
    "CorrectOption": "NaCl"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "What is the chemical formula for sulfuric acid?",
    "OptionA": "H2SO4",
    "OptionB": "HCl",
    "OptionC": "HNO3",
    "OptionD": "H3PO4",
    "CorrectOption": "H2SO4"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "What is the chemical formula for ammonia?",
    "OptionA": "NH3",
    "OptionB": "N2",
    "OptionC": "NO2",
    "OptionD": "H2N2",
    "CorrectOption": "NH3"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "What is the chemical formula for hydrogen peroxide?",
    "OptionA": "H2O",
    "OptionB": "H2O2",
    "OptionC": "HClO",
    "OptionD": "H3PO4",
    "CorrectOption": "H2O2"
  },
  

  
  {
    "Question": "What is the chemical formula for hydrochloric acid?",
    "OptionA": "HCl",
    "OptionB": "H2SO4",
    "OptionC": "HNO3",
    "OptionD": "H3PO4",
    "CorrectOption": "HCl"
  },
  {
    "Question": "What is the chemical symbol for iron?",
    "OptionA": "Ag",
    "OptionB": "Au",
    "OptionC": "Fe",
    "OptionD": "Cu",
    "CorrectOption": "Fe"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "What is the chemical symbol for copper?",
    "OptionA": "Ag",
    "OptionB": "Au",
    "OptionC": "Fe",
    "OptionD": "Cu",
    "CorrectOption": "Cu"
  },

  {
    "Question": "How is Molality defined?",
    "OptionA": "The number of moles of solute per kilogram of solvent",
    "OptionB": "The number of moles of solute per liter of solution",
    "OptionC": "The number of grams of solute per kilogram of solvent",
    "OptionD": "The number of grams of solute per liter of solution",
    "CorrectOption": "The number of moles of solute per kilogram of solvent"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "What does Normality measure?",
    "OptionA": "The number of moles of solute per kilogram of solvent",
    "OptionB": "The number of moles of solute per liter of solution",
    "OptionC": "The equivalent weight of solute per liter of solution",
    "OptionD": "The number of grams of solute per liter of solution",
    "CorrectOption": "The equivalent weight of solute per liter of solution"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "How is Molarity calculated?",
    "OptionA": "Moles of solute / Kilograms of solvent",
    "OptionB": "Moles of solute / Liters of solution",
    "OptionC": "Grams of solute / Kilograms of solvent",
    "OptionD": "Grams of solute / Liters of solution",
    "CorrectOption": "Moles of solute / Liters of solution"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "What is the formula for calculating Molality?",
    "OptionA": "Moles of solute / Kilograms of solvent",
    "OptionB": "Moles of solute / Liters of solution",
    "OptionC": "Grams of solute / Kilograms of solvent",
    "OptionD": "Grams of solute / Liters of solution",
    "CorrectOption": "Moles of solute / Kilograms of solvent"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "In Normality, what is equivalent weight?",
    "OptionA": "The molecular weight of solute",
    "OptionB": "The molar mass of solute",
    "OptionC": "The weight of solute that can donate or accept one mole of electrons",
    "OptionD": "The weight of solute that dissolves in one liter of solution",
    "CorrectOption": "The weight of solute that can donate or accept one mole of electrons"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "What is the unit of Molarity?",
    "OptionA": "mol/kg",
    "OptionB": "mol/L",
    "OptionC": "g/L",
    "OptionD": "g/kg",
    "CorrectOption": "mol/L"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "Which concentration term is temperature-dependent?",
    "OptionA": "Molarity",
    "OptionB": "Molality",
    "OptionC": "Normality",
    "OptionD": "All of the above",
    "CorrectOption": "Molality"
  },

  {
    "Question": "Which group of elements is known as the noble gases?",
    "OptionA": "Group 1",
    "OptionB": "Group 14",
    "OptionC": "Group 18",
    "OptionD": "Group 17",
    "CorrectOption": "Group 18"
  },

  {
    "Question": "Which element is a halogen in Group 17?",
    "OptionA": "Fluorine",
    "OptionB": "Sodium",
    "OptionC": "Aluminum",
    "OptionD": "Potassium",
    "CorrectOption": "Fluorine"
  },
  {
    "Question": "How many periods are there in the periodic table?",
    "OptionA": "6",
    "OptionB": "7",
    "OptionC": "8",
    "OptionD": "9",
    "CorrectOption": "7"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "Which element is a transition metal in Period 4?",
    "OptionA": "Scandium",
    "OptionB": "Titanium",
    "OptionC": "Iron",
    "OptionD": "Zinc",
    "CorrectOption": "Iron"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "What is the most abundant gas in Earth's atmosphere?",
    "OptionA": "Oxygen",
    "OptionB": "Nitrogen",
    "OptionC": "Carbon dioxide",
    "OptionD": "Argon",
    "CorrectOption": "Nitrogen"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Which group of elements is known as alkali metals?",
    "OptionA": "Group 1",
    "OptionB": "Group 2",
    "OptionC": "Group 17",
    "OptionD": "Group 18",
    "CorrectOption": "Group 1"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "What is the general valence electron configuration of alkali metals?",
    "OptionA": "ns^1",
    "OptionB": "ns^2",
    "OptionC": "ns^2np^6",
    "OptionD": "ns^2np^5",
    "CorrectOption": "ns^1"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "Which alkali metal has the lowest atomic number?",
    "OptionA": "Lithium",
    "OptionB": "Sodium",
    "OptionC": "Potassium",
    "OptionD": "Rubidium",
    "CorrectOption": "Lithium"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "Alkali metals are highly reactive due to...",
    "OptionA": "Low ionization energy",
    "OptionB": "High ionization energy",
    "OptionC": "Low electronegativity",
    "OptionD": "High electronegativity",
    "CorrectOption": "Low ionization energy"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "Which of the following is an alkaline earth metal?",
    "OptionA": "Lithium",
    "OptionB": "Sodium",
    "OptionC": "Magnesium",
    "OptionD": "Potassium",
    "CorrectOption": "Magnesium"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "What is the general valence electron configuration of alkaline earth metals?",
    "OptionA": "ns^1",
    "OptionB": "ns^2",
    "OptionC": "ns^2np^6",
    "OptionD": "ns^2np^5",
    "CorrectOption": "ns^2"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "Which alkaline earth metal is found in bones and teeth?",
    "OptionA": "Calcium",
    "OptionB": "Strontium",
    "OptionC": "Barium",
    "OptionD": "Radium",
    "CorrectOption": "Calcium"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "Ammonium ion is represented by the formula...",
    "OptionA": "NH4+",
    "OptionB": "NO3-",
    "OptionC": "SO4^2-",
    "OptionD": "CO3^2-",
    "CorrectOption": "NH4+"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "What is the charge on the ammonium ion?",
    "OptionA": "+1",
    "OptionB": "-1",
    "OptionC": "+2",
    "OptionD": "-2",
    "CorrectOption": "+1"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "Which of the following is an alkali metal?",
    "OptionA": "Rubidium",
    "OptionB": "Beryllium",
    "OptionC": "Magnesium",
    "OptionD": "Aluminum",
    "CorrectOption": "Rubidium"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "The alkali metals react with water to produce...",
    "OptionA": "Oxides",
    "OptionB": "Hydroxides",
    "OptionC": "Carbonates",
    "OptionD": "Sulfides",
    "CorrectOption": "Hydroxides"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "Which alkaline earth metal is commonly used in fireworks to produce a red flame?",
    "OptionA": "Barium",
    "OptionB": "Strontium",
    "OptionC": "Calcium",
    "OptionD": "Magnesium",
    "CorrectOption": "Strontium"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "The alkaline earth metals are located in which group of the periodic table?",
    "OptionA": "Group 1",
    "OptionB": "Group 2",
    "OptionC": "Group 17",
    "OptionD": "Group 18",
    "CorrectOption": "Group 2"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "Which alkali metal is known for forming explosive compounds with water?",
    "OptionA": "Lithium",
    "OptionB": "Sodium",
    "OptionC": "Potassium",
    "OptionD": "Rubidium",
    "CorrectOption": "Potassium"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "The alkaline earth metals have a higher melting point compared to alkali metals due to...",
    "OptionA": "Higher atomic size",
    "OptionB": "Lower atomic size",
    "OptionC": "Higher ionization energy",
    "OptionD": "Lower ionization energy",
    "CorrectOption": "Higher ionization energy"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "Which alkali metal is the most abundant in the Earth's crust?",
    "OptionA": "Lithium",
    "OptionB": "Sodium",
    "OptionC": "Potassium",
    "OptionD": "Rubidium",
    "CorrectOption": "Potassium"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "The formula for the sulfate ion is...",
    "OptionA": "SO4^2-",
    "OptionB": "NO3-",
    "OptionC": "CO3^2-",
    "OptionD": "NH4+",
    "CorrectOption": "SO4^2-"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "What is the charge on the sulfate ion?",
    "OptionA": "+1",
    "OptionB": "-1",
    "OptionC": "+2",
    "OptionD": "-2",
    "CorrectOption": "-2"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "Which of the following is an ammonium compound?",
    "OptionA": "NH4Cl",
    "OptionB": "NaCl",
    "OptionC": "CaCl2",
    "OptionD": "KCl",
    "CorrectOption": "NH4Cl"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "Alkali metals are known for their...",
    "OptionA": "Low reactivity",
    "OptionB": "High reactivity",
    "OptionC": "Stable compounds",
    "OptionD": "Poor conductivity",
    "CorrectOption": "High reactivity"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Which group of elements is known as the carbon group?",
    "OptionA": "Group 1",
    "OptionB": "Group 14",
    "OptionC": "Group 17",
    "OptionD": "Group 18",
    "CorrectOption": "Group 14"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "What is the general valence electron configuration of the carbon group?",
    "OptionA": "ns^1",
    "OptionB": "ns^2",
    "OptionC": "ns^2np^6",
    "OptionD": "ns^2np^4",
    "CorrectOption": "ns^2np^4"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "Which element is the central atom in the carbon group?",
    "OptionA": "Carbon",
    "OptionB": "Silicon",
    "OptionC": "Germanium",
    "OptionD": "Lead",
    "CorrectOption": "Carbon"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "What is the most abundant element in the Earth's crust from the carbon group?",
    "OptionA": "Carbon",
    "OptionB": "Silicon",
    "OptionC": "Germanium",
    "OptionD": "Lead",
    "CorrectOption": "Silicon"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "Phosphorus is commonly found in nature in the form of...",
    "OptionA": "P4 molecules",
    "OptionB": "PO4^3- ions",
    "OptionC": "Pb^2+ ions",
    "OptionD": "PH3 molecules",
    "CorrectOption": "P4 molecules"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "Which element in the oxygen group has the highest electronegativity?",
    "OptionA": "Oxygen",
    "OptionB": "Sulfur",
    "OptionC": "Selenium",
    "OptionD": "Tellurium",
    "CorrectOption": "Oxygen"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "Which of the following is an allotrope of oxygen?",
    "OptionA": "O2",
    "OptionB": "O3",
    "OptionC": "O4",
    "OptionD": "O5",
    "CorrectOption": "O3"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "What is the general valence electron configuration of the oxygen group?",
    "OptionA": "ns^1",
    "OptionB": "ns^2",
    "OptionC": "ns^2np^6",
    "OptionD": "ns^2np^2",
    "CorrectOption": "ns^2np^4"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "Which of the following is a common property of the carbon group elements?",
    "OptionA": "High electronegativity",
    "OptionB": "Low melting points",
    "OptionC": "Metallic character",
    "OptionD": "Low reactivity",
    "CorrectOption": "Low melting points"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "Ozone (O3) is most commonly found in which layer of the Earth's atmosphere?",
    "OptionA": "Troposphere",
    "OptionB": "Stratosphere",
    "OptionC": "Mesosphere",
    "OptionD": "Exosphere",
    "CorrectOption": "Stratosphere"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "Which element in the carbon group has the highest melting point?",
    "OptionA": "Carbon",
    "OptionB": "Silicon",
    "OptionC": "Germanium",
    "OptionD": "Lead",
    "CorrectOption": "Lead"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "Phosphorus is an essential component of which biological molecule?",
    "OptionA": "Proteins",
    "OptionB": "Lipids",
    "OptionC": "Nucleic acids",
    "OptionD": "Carbohydrates",
    "CorrectOption": "Nucleic acids"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "The element in the oxygen group with the lowest atomic number is...",
    "OptionA": "Oxygen",
    "OptionB": "Sulfur",
    "OptionC": "Selenium",
    "OptionD": "Tellurium",
    "CorrectOption": "Oxygen"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "Which of the following is a property of phosphorus?",
    "OptionA": "Exists as diatomic molecules",
    "OptionB": "Forms a wide variety of compounds",
    "OptionC": "Metallic character",
    "OptionD": "High melting point",
    "CorrectOption": "Forms a wide variety of compounds"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "The oxygen group elements are commonly found in nature in the form of...",
    "OptionA": "Diatomic molecules",
    "OptionB": "Ions",
    "OptionC": "Allotropes",
    "OptionD": "Triatomic molecules",
    "CorrectOption": "Diatomic molecules"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "Which element in the carbon group is used in the production of semiconductors?",
    "OptionA": "Carbon",
    "OptionB": "Silicon",
    "OptionC": "Germanium",
    "OptionD": "Lead",
    "CorrectOption": "Germanium"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "The oxygen group elements exhibit a trend of increasing...",
    "OptionA": "Atomic radius",
    "OptionB": "Electronegativity",
    "OptionC": "Melting point",
    "OptionD": "Ionization energy",
    "CorrectOption": "Electronegativity"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "Which element in the carbon group is known for its ability to form long chains in organic compounds?",
    "OptionA": "Carbon",
    "OptionB": "Silicon",
    "OptionC": "Germanium",
    "OptionD": "Lead",
    "CorrectOption": "Carbon"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "The allotrope of phosphorus that consists of P4 tetrahedra is known as...",
    "OptionA": "Red phosphorus",
    "OptionB": "White phosphorus",
    "OptionC": "Black phosphorus",
    "OptionD": "Yellow phosphorus",
    "CorrectOption": "White phosphorus"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "Which type of hydrocarbon contains only single bonds between carbon atoms?",
    "OptionA": "Alkane",
    "OptionB": "Alkene",
    "OptionC": "Alkyne",
    "OptionD": "Aromatic",
    "CorrectOption": "Alkane"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "What is the general formula for alkanes?",
    "OptionA": "CnH2n",
    "OptionB": "CnH2n+2",
    "OptionC": "CnHn",
    "OptionD": "CnHn-2",
    "CorrectOption": "CnH2n+2"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "How many carbon atoms are there in butane?",
    "OptionA": "2",
    "OptionB": "3",
    "OptionC": "4",
    "OptionD": "5",
    "CorrectOption": "4"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "Which hydrocarbon has a triple bond between carbon atoms?",
    "OptionA": "Alkane",
    "OptionB": "Alkene",
    "OptionC": "Alkyne",
    "OptionD": "Aromatic",
    "CorrectOption": "Alkyne"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "What is the general formula for alkenes?",
    "OptionA": "CnH2n",
    "OptionB": "CnH2n+2",
    "OptionC": "CnHn",
    "OptionD": "CnHn-2",
    "CorrectOption": "CnH2n"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "Which of the following is an example of an alkene?",
    "OptionA": "Methane",
    "OptionB": "Ethane",
    "OptionC": "Propene",
    "OptionD": "Butane",
    "CorrectOption": "Propene"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "How many pi bonds are there in a molecule of ethene?",
    "OptionA": "1",
    "OptionB": "2",
    "OptionC": "3",
    "OptionD": "4",
    "CorrectOption": "1"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "What is the general formula for alkynes?",
    "OptionA": "CnH2n",
    "OptionB": "CnH2n+2",
    "OptionC": "CnHn",
    "OptionD": "CnHn-2",
    "CorrectOption": "CnH2n-2"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "Which of the following is an example of an alkyne?",
    "OptionA": "Methane",
    "OptionB": "Ethene",
    "OptionC": "Propyne",
    "OptionD": "Butane",
    "CorrectOption": "Propyne"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "How many sigma bonds are there in a molecule of butyne?",
    "OptionA": "1",
    "OptionB": "2",
    "OptionC": "3",
    "OptionD": "4",
    "CorrectOption": "3"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "Which hydrocarbon has a double bond between carbon atoms?",
    "OptionA": "Alkane",
    "OptionB": "Alkene",
    "OptionC": "Alkyne",
    "OptionD": "Aromatic",
    "CorrectOption": "Alkene"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "Which of the following is an example of an alkane?",
    "OptionA": "Methane",
    "OptionB": "Ethene",
    "OptionC": "Propane",
    "OptionD": "Butene",
    "CorrectOption": "Propane"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "How many hydrogen atoms are there in a molecule of pentane?",
    "OptionA": "10",
    "OptionB": "12",
    "OptionC": "14",
    "OptionD": "16",
    "CorrectOption": "12"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "What is the general formula for cycloalkanes?",
    "OptionA": "CnH2n",
    "OptionB": "CnH2n+2",
    "OptionC": "CnHn",
    "OptionD": "CnHn-2",
    "CorrectOption": "CnH2n"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "Which of the following is an example of a cycloalkane?",
    "OptionA": "Cyclopropane",
    "OptionB": "Butane",
    "OptionC": "Propene",
    "OptionD": "Methane",
    "CorrectOption": "Cyclopropane"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "How many carbon-carbon double bonds are there in a molecule of hexene?",
    "OptionA": "1",
    "OptionB": "2",
    "OptionC": "3",
    "OptionD": "4",
    "CorrectOption": "1"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "What is the general formula for cycloalkenes?",
    "OptionA": "CnH2n",
    "OptionB": "CnH2n+2",
    "OptionC": "CnHn",
    "OptionD": "CnHn-2",
    "CorrectOption": "CnH2n-2"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "Which of the following is an example of a cycloalkene?",
    "OptionA": "Cyclopropane",
    "OptionB": "Butene",
    "OptionC": "Cyclobutene",
    "OptionD": "Methane",
    "CorrectOption": "Cyclobutene"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "How many sigma bonds are there in a molecule of octyne?",
    "OptionA": "5",
    "OptionB": "6",
    "OptionC": "7",
    "OptionD": "8",
    "CorrectOption": "7"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "Which of the following is an example of an aromatic hydrocarbon?",
    "OptionA": "Methane",
    "OptionB": "Ethene",
    "OptionC": "Benzene",
    "OptionD": "Propane",
    "CorrectOption": "Benzene"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "How many pi bonds are there in a molecule of benzene?",
    "OptionA": "1",
    "OptionB": "2",
    "OptionC": "3",
    "OptionD": "4",
    "CorrectOption": "3"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "What is the general formula for aromatic hydrocarbons?",
    "OptionA": "CnH2n",
    "OptionB": "CnH2n+2",
    "OptionC": "CnHn",
    "OptionD": "CnHn-2",
    "CorrectOption": "CnHn"
  },

  {
    "Question": "In a sigma bond, the overlap of atomic orbitals occurs along the...",
    "OptionA": "Nodal plane",
    "OptionB": "Nuclear axis",
    "OptionC": "Electron cloud",
    "OptionD": "Spin axis",
    "CorrectOption": "Nuclear axis"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "Which type of bond is formed by the head-on overlap of atomic orbitals?",
    "OptionA": "Sigma bond",
    "OptionB": "Pi bond",
    "OptionC": "Ionic bond",
    "OptionD": "Covalent bond",
    "CorrectOption": "Sigma bond"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "A pi bond is formed by the overlap of atomic orbitals along the...",
    "OptionA": "Nodal plane",
    "OptionB": "Nuclear axis",
    "OptionC": "Electron cloud",
    "OptionD": "Spin axis",
    "CorrectOption": "Nodal plane"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "Which type of bond is formed by the sideways overlap of p-orbitals?",
    "OptionA": "Sigma bond",
    "OptionB": "Pi bond",
    "OptionC": "Ionic bond",
    "OptionD": "Covalent bond",
    "CorrectOption": "Pi bond"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "In an ionic bond, electrons are...",
    "OptionA": "Shared",
    "OptionB": "Transferred",
    "OptionC": "Overlapped",
    "OptionD": "Not involved",
    "CorrectOption": "Transferred"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "Which type of bond involves the complete transfer of electrons from one atom to another?",
    "OptionA": "Sigma bond",
    "OptionB": "Pi bond",
    "OptionC": "Ionic bond",
    "OptionD": "Covalent bond",
    "CorrectOption": "Ionic bond"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "In a covalent bond, electrons are...",
    "OptionA": "Shared",
    "OptionB": "Transferred",
    "OptionC": "Overlapped",
    "OptionD": "Not involved",
    "CorrectOption": "Shared"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "Which type of bond involves the sharing of electrons between two atoms?",
    "OptionA": "Sigma bond",
    "OptionB": "Pi bond",
    "OptionC": "Ionic bond",
    "OptionD": "Covalent bond",
    "CorrectOption": "Covalent bond"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "A coordinate covalent bond is formed when...",
    "OptionA": "Electrons are shared",
    "OptionB": "Electrons are transferred",
    "OptionC": "One atom provides both shared electrons",
    "OptionD": "Electrons are overlapped",
    "CorrectOption": "One atom provides both shared electrons"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "Which type of bond is characterized by the sharing of electrons with unequal sharing leading to partial charges?",
    "OptionA": "Nonpolar covalent bond",
    "OptionB": "Polar covalent bond",
    "OptionC": "Ionic bond",
    "OptionD": "Sigma bond",
    "CorrectOption": "Polar covalent bond"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "A triple bond consists of...",
    "OptionA": "One sigma bond and one pi bond",
    "OptionB": "Three sigma bonds",
    "OptionC": "Three pi bonds",
    "OptionD": "Two sigma bonds and one pi bond",
    "CorrectOption": "One sigma bond and two pi bonds"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "In a nonpolar covalent bond, the atoms...",
    "OptionA": "Have similar electronegativities",
    "OptionB": "Have different electronegativities",
    "OptionC": "Transfer electrons",
    "OptionD": "Have no electrons",
    "CorrectOption": "Have similar electronegativities"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "A sigma bond is always present in...",
    "OptionA": "Single bonds",
    "OptionB": "Double bonds",
    "OptionC": "Triple bonds",
    "OptionD": "All of the above",
    "CorrectOption": "All of the above"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "Which type of bond is formed by the overlap of sp3 hybrid orbitals?",
    "OptionA": "Sigma bond",
    "OptionB": "Pi bond",
    "OptionC": "Ionic bond",
    "OptionD": "Covalent bond",
    "CorrectOption": "Sigma bond"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "In a polar covalent bond, the more electronegative atom...",
    "OptionA": "Donates electrons",
    "OptionB": "Accepts electrons",
    "OptionC": "Attracts shared electrons more strongly",
    "OptionD": "Does not participate",
    "CorrectOption": "Attracts shared electrons more strongly"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "A sigma bond is always formed by...",
    "OptionA": "p-p overlap",
    "OptionB": "s-s overlap",
    "OptionC": "s-p overlap",
    "OptionD": "p-d overlap",
    "CorrectOption": "s-s overlap"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "Which type of bond is formed by the side-to-side overlap of atomic orbitals?",
    "OptionA": "Sigma bond",
    "OptionB": "Pi bond",
    "OptionC": "Ionic bond",
    "OptionD": "Covalent bond",
    "CorrectOption": "Pi bond"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "The shape of a molecule with a triple bond is...",
    "OptionA": "Linear",
    "OptionB": "Trigonal planar",
    "OptionC": "Tetrahedral",
    "OptionD": "Linear or bent",
    "CorrectOption": "Linear or bent"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "In a coordinate covalent bond, the atom providing both shared electrons is called the...",
    "OptionA": "Donor",
    "OptionB": "Acceptor",
    "OptionC": "Cation",
    "OptionD": "Anion",
    "CorrectOption": "Donor"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "Which type of bond is formed by the end-to-end overlap of p-orbitals?",
    "OptionA": "Sigma bond",
    "OptionB": "Pi bond",
    "OptionC": "Ionic bond",
    "OptionD": "Covalent bond",
    "CorrectOption": "Sigma bond"
  },

  {
    "Question": "What is the chemical formula of borax?",
    "OptionA": "NaOH",
    "OptionB": "Na2CO3",
    "OptionC": "Na2B4O7·10H2O",
    "OptionD": "KOH",
    "CorrectOption": "Na2B4O7·10H2O"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "Caustic soda is another name for which compound?",
    "OptionA": "Sodium bicarbonate",
    "OptionB": "Sodium hydroxide",
    "OptionC": "Sodium chloride",
    "OptionD": "Sodium carbonate",
    "CorrectOption": "Sodium hydroxide"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "What is the common name for sodium carbonate decahydrate?",
    "OptionA": "Baking soda",
    "OptionB": "Washing soda",
    "OptionC": "Caustic soda",
    "OptionD": "Borax",
    "CorrectOption": "Washing soda"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "Which of the following is a physical change?",
    "OptionA": "Burning wood",
    "OptionB": "Boiling water",
    "OptionC": "Digesting food",
    "OptionD": "Rusting iron",
    "CorrectOption": "Boiling water"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "What happens when you dissolve washing soda in water?",
    "OptionA": "It releases carbon dioxide",
    "OptionB": "It becomes acidic",
    "OptionC": "It forms a basic solution",
    "OptionD": "It turns into a gas",
    "CorrectOption": "It forms a basic solution"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "Which of the following is a chemical change?",
    "OptionA": "Melting ice",
    "OptionB": "Mixing salt and sand",
    "OptionC": "Burning paper",
    "OptionD": "Cutting a piece of paper",
    "CorrectOption": "Burning paper"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "What is the primary component of borax that imparts its cleaning properties?",
    "OptionA": "Sodium bicarbonate",
    "OptionB": "Boric acid",
    "OptionC": "Sodium carbonate",
    "OptionD": "Sodium hydroxide",
    "CorrectOption": "Boric acid"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "Which of the following is a property of caustic soda (sodium hydroxide)?",
    "OptionA": "It is acidic in nature",
    "OptionB": "It is a strong base",
    "OptionC": "It is a gas at room temperature",
    "OptionD": "It is a metal",
    "CorrectOption": "It is a strong base"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "When washing soda is heated, it loses water molecules and forms...",
    "OptionA": "Sodium bicarbonate",
    "OptionB": "Sodium carbonate",
    "OptionC": "Sodium chloride",
    "OptionD": "Sodium hydroxide",
    "CorrectOption": "Sodium carbonate"
  },
  
  {
    "Question": "Which of the following is a physical change?",
    "OptionA": "Rusting of iron",
    "OptionB": "Freezing water",
    "OptionC": "Burning wood",
    "OptionD": "Digesting food",
    "CorrectOption": "Freezing water"
  },

  {
    "Question": "When baking soda (sodium bicarbonate) is heated strongly, it decomposes to form a new compound and a gas. The gas produced is:",
    "OptionA": "Chlorine gas",
    "OptionB": "Carbon dioxide",
    "OptionC": "Oxygen gas",
    "OptionD": "Water vapor",
    "CorrectOption": "Carbon dioxide"
    },
    
    {
    "Question": "Slaked lime (calcium hydroxide) reacts with carbon dioxide in the air to form a white powder. This powder is:",
    "OptionA": "Calcium carbonate",
    "OptionB": "Calcium chloride",
    "OptionC": "Calcium oxide",
    "OptionD": "Calcium sulfate",
    "CorrectOption": "Calcium carbonate"
    },
    
    {
    "Question": "When ammonia gas (NH3) reacts with water, it forms a solution with a pungent smell. This solution is:",
    "OptionA": "Ammonium chloride",
    "OptionB": "Ammonium nitrate",
    "OptionC": "Ammonium hydroxide",
    "OptionD": "Ammonium sulfate",
    "CorrectOption": "Ammonium hydroxide"
    },
    
    {
    "Question": "Epsom salt (magnesium sulfate) can be produced by reacting magnesium chloride with:",
    "OptionA": "Calcium carbonate",
    "OptionB": "Sodium hydroxide",
    "OptionC": "Sulfuric acid",
    "OptionD": "Water",
    "CorrectOption": "Sulfuric acid"
    },
    
    {
    "Question": "The main component of cement is calcium silicate, which is formed by the reaction of:",
    "OptionA": "Calcium carbonate and sand",
    "OptionB": "Calcium chloride and clay",
    "OptionC": "Calcium oxide and sand",
    "OptionD": "Calcium sulfate and water",
    "CorrectOption": "Calcium oxide and sand"
    },
    
    {
    "Question": "During the Haber-Bosch process, nitrogen and hydrogen react under high pressure and temperature with a catalyst to produce:",
    "OptionA": "Ammonia",
    "OptionB": "Carbon dioxide",
    "OptionC": "Methane",
    "OptionD": "Nitric acid",
    "CorrectOption": "Ammonia"
    },
    
    {
    "Question": "When iron reacts with sulfuric acid, it produces iron sulfate and a gas. The gas produced is:",
    "OptionA": "Carbon dioxide",
    "OptionB": "Hydrogen",
    "OptionC": "Nitrogen",
    "OptionD": "Oxygen",
    "CorrectOption": "Hydrogen"
    },
    
    {
    "Question": "Bleaching powder, a common disinfectant, is produced by the reaction of chlorine with:",
    "OptionA": "Calcium carbonate",
    "OptionB": "Calcium hydroxide",
    "OptionC": "Sodium chloride",
    "OptionD": "Sodium hydroxide",
    "CorrectOption": "Calcium hydroxide"
    },
    
    {
    "Question": "Plaster of Paris (calcium sulfate hemihydrate) is formed when gypsum (calcium sulfate dihydrate) loses water molecules. This process is called:",
    "OptionA": "Calcination",
    "OptionB": "Dehydration",
    "OptionC": "Decomposition",
    "OptionD": "Precipitation",
    "CorrectOption": "Dehydration"
    },
    
    {
    "Question": "Borax (sodium tetraborate) is a commonly used cleaning agent. It is produced by the reaction of:",
    "OptionA": "Boric acid and sodium carbonate",
    "OptionB": "Boron trioxide and sodium chloride",
    "OptionC": "Sodium bicarbonate and borax",
    "OptionD": "Water and borax",
    "CorrectOption": "Boric acid and sodium carbonate"
    },

    {
      "Question": "The element neon has how many valence electrons?",
      "OptionA": "1",
      "OptionB": "2",
      "OptionC": "8",
      "OptionD": "18",
      "CorrectOption": "8"
      },
      
      {
      "Question": "Which element is a common component of table salt?",
      "OptionA": "Calcium",
      "OptionB": "Chlorine",
      "OptionC": "Iron",
      "OptionD": "Silver",
      "CorrectOption": "Chlorine"
      },
      
      {
      "Question": "The pH of a neutral solution is approximately:",
      "OptionA": "2",
      "OptionB": "5",
      "OptionC": "7",
      "OptionD": "10",
      "CorrectOption": "7"
      },
      
      {
      "Question": "Water (H2O) is a molecule because it is:",
      "OptionA": "a pure element",
      "OptionB": "a mixture of elements",
      "OptionC": "made up of two or more atoms bonded together",
      "OptionD": "a liquid at room temperature",
      "CorrectOption": "made up of two or more atoms bonded together"
      },
      
      {
      "Question": "Which of the following is NOT a physical property of a substance?",
      "OptionA": "color",
      "OptionB": "density",
      "OptionC": "chemical reactivity",
      "OptionD": "melting point",
      "CorrectOption": "chemical reactivity"
      },
      
      {
      "Question": "The balanced chemical equation for the combustion of methane (CH4) is:",
      "OptionA": "CH4 + O2 → CO2 + H2O",
      "OptionB": "CH4 + 2O2 → CO2 + 2H2O",
      "OptionC": "CH4 + O2 → CH3OH + H2O",
      "OptionD": "CH4 + 2O2 → CO + 2H2",
      "CorrectOption": "CH4 + 2O2 → CO2 + 2H2O"
      },
      
      {
      "Question": "Which element is a liquid at room temperature?",
      "OptionA": "Bromine",
      "OptionB": "Gold",
      "OptionC": "Magnesium",
      "OptionD": "Sulfur",
      "CorrectOption": "Bromine"
      },
      
      {
      "Question": "What is the symbol for the element sodium?",
      "OptionA": "Ca",
      "OptionB": "Cu",
      "OptionC": "Na",
      "OptionD": "Zn",
      "CorrectOption": "Na"
      },
      
      {
      "Question": "The law of conservation of mass states that:",
      "OptionA": "the total amount of energy in a closed system remains constant",
      "OptionB": "the total amount of matter in a closed system remains constant",
      "OptionC": "the total amount of heat in a closed system remains constant",
      "OptionD": "the total amount of light in a closed system remains constant",
      "CorrectOption": "the total amount of matter in a closed system remains constant"
      },
      
      {
      "Question": "Which type of bond is formed when atoms share electrons?",
      "OptionA": "ionic bond",
      "OptionB": "covalent bond",
      "OptionC": "metallic bond",
      "OptionD": "hydrogen bond",
      "CorrectOption": "covalent bond"
      },
      
      {
      "Question": "The noble gases are unreactive because:",
      "OptionA": "they have full valence electron shells",
      "OptionB": "they are all metals",
      "OptionC": "they are all nonmetals",
      "OptionD": "they are all liquids at room temperature",
      "CorrectOption": "they have full valence electron shells"
      },
      
      {
      "Question": "What is the name of the process when a liquid changes to a gas?",
      "OptionA": "condensation",
      "OptionB": "deposition",
      "OptionC": "evaporation",
      "OptionD": "sublimation",
      "CorrectOption": "evaporation"
      },
      {
        "Question": "Which vitamin is essential for the proper functioning of vision?",
        "OptionA": "Vitamin A",
        "OptionB": "Vitamin C",
        "OptionC": "Vitamin D",
        "OptionD": "Vitamin K",
        "CorrectOption": "Vitamin A"
      },
      
      {
        "Question": "Proteins are composed of amino acids. How many essential amino acids are there?",
        "OptionA": "5",
        "OptionB": "9",
        "OptionC": "12",
        "OptionD": "20",
        "CorrectOption": "9"
      },
      
      {
        "Question": "Which of the following is a water-soluble vitamin?",
        "OptionA": "Vitamin A",
        "OptionB": "Vitamin C",
        "OptionC": "Vitamin D",
        "OptionD": "Vitamin E",
        "CorrectOption": "Vitamin C"
      },
      
      {
        "Question": "Lipids include which of the following substances?",
        "OptionA": "Sugars",
        "OptionB": "Amino acids",
        "OptionC": "Fatty acids",
        "OptionD": "Nucleotides",
        "CorrectOption": "Fatty acids"
      },
      
      {
        "Question": "Which vitamin is known as the 'sunshine vitamin'?",
        "OptionA": "Vitamin A",
        "OptionB": "Vitamin C",
        "OptionC": "Vitamin D",
        "OptionD": "Vitamin K",
        "CorrectOption": "Vitamin D"
      },
      
      {
        "Question": "The main function of proteins in the body is to...",
        "OptionA": "Provide energy",
        "OptionB": "Build and repair tissues",
        "OptionC": "Act as antioxidants",
        "OptionD": "Assist in blood clotting",
        "CorrectOption": "Build and repair tissues"
      },
      
      {
        "Question": "Which lipid is a major component of cell membranes?",
        "OptionA": "Triglycerides",
        "OptionB": "Phospholipids",
        "OptionC": "Steroids",
        "OptionD": "Waxes",
        "CorrectOption": "Phospholipids"
      },
      
      {
        "Question": "Vitamin K is essential for which process in the body?",
        "OptionA": "Blood clotting",
        "OptionB": "Bone formation",
        "OptionC": "Vision",
        "OptionD": "Immune system function",
        "CorrectOption": "Blood clotting"
      },
      
      {
        "Question": "Complete proteins, which contain all essential amino acids, are commonly found in...",
        "OptionA": "Fruits",
        "OptionB": "Vegetables",
        "OptionC": "Meat and dairy products",
        "OptionD": "Nuts and seeds",
        "CorrectOption": "Meat and dairy products"
      }
  
  

  
  
  
  
]
